Guide to the Robert Gorham Davis Collection
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Robert Gorham Davis Collection,
1908-1978
Davis, Robert Gorham, collector.
0.5 linear ft (155 items in 1 box).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078683
Biographical Note
Professor of English at Columbia University.
Scope and Content
A group of literary manuscripts, including three letters written to Professor Robert Gorham Davis by Ezra Pound, the holograph draft by Dorothy Parker of her address delivered at the Esquire Magazine Symposium in October 1958, and two manuscripts of James T. Farrell, one containing holograph drafts of poems, and the other being a carbon copy typescript of various chapters from WHAT TIME COLLECTS. Also, approximately 65 letters from Ella Winter in the late 1930s, discussing politics, writing, and their social circle; approximately 25 letters from Laura Riding written in the late 1970s on language and, in particular, her book RATIONAL DEFINITION; and letters from James T. Farrell, Granville Hicks, Richard Rovere, and others.
Scope and Content
The collection contained a journal kept by William McKendry from the end of 1778 to January 1780, portions of which relate to General John Sullivan's campaign against the Iroquois Indians. The journal is cataloged separately under the call number: X973.309\M196.
Arrangement
The colletion is arranged into three series:
Series I: Catalogued Correspondence, 1908-1976
Series II: Manuscripts, 1933-1963
Series III: Arranged Material, 1932-1978
Subjects
Rovere, Richard Halworth, 1915-; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972.; Parker, Dorothy, 1893-1967.; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979.; McKendry, William.; Sullivan, John, 1740-1795.; Winter, Ella, 1898-1980.; Riding, Laura, 1901-1991.; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; New York (State)--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--Campaigns.; Iroquois Indians--Wars.; Indians of North America--New York (State); Sullivan's Indian Campaign, 1779.; Literature.; Addresses.; Poems.; Manuscripts.; Diaries.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1965 M-65 Davis, Robert Gorham Gift
Gift of Robert G. Davis, 1965 and 1983.
- Series I: Catalogued Correspondence, 1908-1976
  - Arvin Newton
    - 1936 January 13 (Box 1)
    - 1936 January 15 (Box 1)
    - 1936 January 18 (Box 1)
    - 1936 March 1 (Box 1)
    - 1936 May 21 (Box 1)
    - 1937 June 19 (Box 1)
  - Chase, Richard, 1953 March 26 (Box 1)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1970 October 16 (Box 1)
  - Farrell, James T.
    - 1958 June 14 (Box 1)
    - 1976 July 19 (Box 1)
    - 1976 September 2 (Box 1)
  - Frank, Waldo, 1932 March (Box 1)
  - Freeman, Joseph to Granville Hicks, 1933 December 15 (Box 1)
  - Hicks, Granville
    - 1940 January 7 (Box 1)
    - 1953 March 21 (Box 1)
  - Hillyer, Robert
    - 1930 October 22 (Box 1)
    - 1934 June 12 (Box 1)
    - 1937 November 6 (Box 1)
  - Humphries, Rolfe, 1936 January 18 (Box 1)
  - Johns, Orrick, 1935 February 12 (Box 1)
  - Lichtenwanger, William, 1960 July 26 (Box 1)
  - Lowenfels, Walter, 1936 July 7 (Box 1)
  - Maxwell, William, 1943 August 6 (Box 1)
  - Neff, Emery
    - 1968 October 11 (with carbon reply) (Box 1)
    - 1968 November 4 (Box 1)
  - Pound, Ezra
    - to Claud Cockburn, 1928 May 31 (Box 1)
    - to Mr. Brooks, 1933 March 28 (Box 1)
    - to Robert G. Davis, 1933 May 21 (Box 1)
    - to Robert G. Davis, 1940s (Box 1)
  - Putnam, Herbert to Mrs. Austin Holden
    - 1908 January 2 (Box 1)
    - 1908 December 19 (Box 1)
  - Rahv, Philip
    - 1934 June 7 (Box 1)
    - 1934 June 29 (Box 1)
    - 1935 July 30 (Box 1)
  - Raiziss, Sonia, 1973 December 20, 1974 May 9 (with carbon of related letter) (Box 1)
  - Riding, Laura
    - 1973 December 9 (Box 1)
    - 1974 January 15 (Box 1)
    - 1974 March 7 (Box 1)
    - 1974 March 8 (with copies of two related letters) (Box 1)
    - 1974 March 20 (with carbon reply) (Box 1)
    - 1974 April 15 (Box 1)
    - 1974 April 21 (6 page draft reply) (Box 1)
    - 1974 July 16 (Box 1)
    - 1974 August 2 (with carbon reply) (Box 1)
    - 1974 September 19 (with carbon reply and draft of related letter) (Box 1)
    - 1974 December 13 (with draft of related letter) (Box 1)
    - 1975 January 11 (with envelope and copy of related letter) (Box 1)
    - 1975 February 2 (Box 1)
    - 1975 February 19 (Box 1)
    - 1975 March 3 (Box 1)
    - 1975 June 4 (with related item) (Box 1)
    - 1975 June 20 (with carbon copy of letter and photocopy of related item) (Box 1)
    - 1975 June 25 (Box 1)
    - 1975 July 10 (Box 1)
    - 1975 July 10 (with carbon reply) (Box 1)
    - 1975 July 26 (Box 1)
    - 1975 August 16 (with carbon reply) (Box 1)
    - 1975 August 31 (with carbon reply) (Box 1)
    - 1975 September 10 (with carbon reply) (Box 1)
    - circa 1975 September (on card with carbon fragment of related letter) (Box 1)
  - Rovere, Richard H.
    - 1952 July 3 (Box 1)
    - 1953 March 25 (Box 1)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M. Jr., 1952 July 8 (Box 1)
  - Schneider, Isidor
    - 1935 March 21 (Box 1)
    - 1935 March 26 (Box 1)
    - 1935 May 31 (Box 1)
    - 1936 January 7 (Box 1)
    - 1936 January 14 (Box 1)
  - West, Ray Benedict Jr., 1950 April 20 (with copies of two related letters) (Box 1)
  - Winter, Ella
    - circa 1937, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 September (fragment of longer letter), (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 September 20 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 October 2 (Box 1)
    - 1937 October 6 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 October 7 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 October 11 (possibly fragment of two different letters) (Box 1)
    - 1937 October 19-20 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 November (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 November 3 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 November 8 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 November 13 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 November 24 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 November 28 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 December 7, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1937 December 9 (Box 1)
    - circa 1937 December 14 (Box 1)
    - 1937 December 29 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938, (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 January (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 January 3 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 January 4 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 January 5 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 January 6 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 January 8 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 January 17 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 February (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 February 2 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 February 4 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 February 16 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 March (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 March 22 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 April 15 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 April 26 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 April 27 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 May (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1938 June 9 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 July 21 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 August 20 (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 October (Box 1)
    - circa 1938 October 6 (Box 1)
    - 1938 October 24 (Box 1)
    - 1939 January 10 (Box 1)
    - 1939 March 9 (Box 1)
    - 1939 April 29 (Box 1)
    - circa 1939 May (Box 1)
    - 1939 May 4 (Box 1)
    - circa 1939 September 29 (Box 1)
    - 1939 October 3 (Box 1)
    - circa 1939 October 15 (Box 1)
    - 1939 December 6 (Box 1)
    - circa 1940 January (Box 1)
    - circa 1940 May 28 (Box 1)
    - circa 1940 June 3 (Box 1)
    - 1940 October 3 (Box 1)
    - circa 1940 November 15 (with draft of related letter and draft of related manuscript) (Box 1)
  - Winters, Yvor to Hiram Haydn
    - 1950 January 8 (Box 1)
    - 1950 January 10 (Box 1)
- Series II: Manuscripts, 1933-1963
  - Farrell, James T.
    - Fragment: Golden Youth (poem) (inscribed to Robert Gorham Davis), 1963 (Box 1)
    - Spring Poem (inscribed to Robert Gorham Davis), 1963 (Box 1)
    - What Time Collections (Chapters 6, 23, 30, 31, 39, 40, 44, 47, 53) (typescript of second draft, with corrections and emendations by Farrell, signed by Farrell at Chapter 39, page 675), circa 1963 (Box 1)
  - Parker, Dorothy--Address Delivered at the Esquire Magazine Symposium, 1958 October (Box 1)
  - Pound, Ezra--The Social Credit Proposals by C.H. Douglas (notes on by Ezra Pound), circa 1933 (Box 1)
  - Thomas, Dylan--"Queen Edith Sitwell and Princess Marianne Moore on Their First Meeting" (drawing with caption, photostat), circa 1952 (Box 1)
- Series III: Arranged Material
  - Correspondence, 1933-1978 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1932-1949 (Box 1)
  - (Box 1)